Guide to the Joseph Stewart Fruton Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Sayre, David
Scannone, Hector
Scatchard, George
Schadewaldt, Hans
Schales, Otto
Schatz, Gottfried
Schechter, Israel
Scheraga, Harold A.
Schiff, Judith A.
Schiller, Peter W.
Schleich, Hans
Schlenk, Fritz
Schlumberger, Simone
Schmidt, Benno A.
Schmidt, G.M.J.
Schmidt, Gerhard
Schmir, Gaston L.
Schmitt, Francis O.
Schneider, Howard A.
Schowen, Richard L.
Schrader, George A,
Schramm, Gerhard
Schubert, Hermann
Schubert, Marcelle
Schultze, Max O.
Schuman, Hanry
Schwarz, David
Schweigert, Bernard S.
Schwyzer, Robert
Sciarini, Louis J.
Science
Scientific American
Scoffone, Ernesto
Scott, A. Ian
Seifriz, William
Seitz, Frederick
Semenza, Giorgio
Semenov, Anatoly N.
Senn, Milton J.E.
Servos, John W.
Setton, Kenneth M.
Shafer, Jules A.
Shamin, Aleksei N.
Shannon, James A.
Sharon, Nathan
Shaw, George Bernard
Shedlovsky, Theodore
Sheehan, John C.
Shelesnyak, Moses C.
Shemin, David
Shemyakin, Mikhail M.
Sherman, James M.
Shiba, Tetsuo
Shilen, Ronald
Shimazono, Norio
Shively, John E.
Shimonishi, Yasutsugu
Shively, John E.
Siekevits, Philip
Silbert, Albert
Silbert, Daniel
Silbert, Elizabeth
Silbert, Miriam
Silva, Paul C.
Silver, Marc S.
Silverman, Joel P.
Silverman, Morris
Simmonds, Sofia
Simonovich, Louis
Simpson, Hartley
Simpson, Melvin V.
Singer, Maxine F.
Sinnott, Edmund W.
Sinsheimer, Robert L.
Sizer, Irwin W.
Skinner, B. Frederick
Skinner, Dorothy M.
Slater, Edward C.
Slater, Stanley
Sligar, Stephen G.
Sloan, Alfred P.
Sloan, Gary
Sloan, Philip R.
Sluyterman, L.A.
Smeaton, William A.
Smith, Cyril Stanley
Smith, Emil L.
Smith, Homer W.
Smith, Ora
Smith, Roberts A.
Smith, Sam
Smith, Virginia A.
Smyth, Derek G.
Smyth, Henry D.
Smythe, Carl V.
Snell, Christopher R.
Snell, Esmond E.
Snoke, John E.
Snow, Charles Percy
Snyder, Stephen
Söll, Dieter G.
Solomon, Arthur K.
Solomon, Richard L.
Sonneborn, Tracy M.
Sorm, Frantisek
Spencer, Allen
Spiegelman, Sol
Spiro, Karl
Spitzer, Eric
Sprinson, David
Srere, Paul A.
Sribney, Michael
Srinivasan, P.R.
Staber, Hermann T.
Stadie, William C.
Stadtman, Earl R.
Stadtman, Thressa C.
Stahmann, Mark A.
Stahnke, Joachim
Stamp, Trevor
Stanier, Roger Y.
Stanley, Wendell M.
Stanton, Madeline
Stark, George R.
Starkoff, B.J.
Stashwick, Tad
Stein, Olga
Stein, William H.
Steinberg, Daniel
Steiner, Donald F.
Steinhardt, Jacinto
Steinmann, Howard M.
Steitz, Joan A.
Stenger, Joseph
Stent, Gunther S.
Stephens, George R.
Stern, Joseph
Stern, Kurt G.
Sternberg, Charles A.
Sternberg, Moshe Z.
Stetten, DeWitt
Stevens, Audrey
Stevens, Charles Edward
Stevens, Richard L.
Stevenson, Lloyd G.
Steward, Frederick C.
Stewart, Walter W.
Stock, C. Chester
Stoddard, Carlos F.
Stokes, Jacob L.
Stokinger, Herbert E.
Stolzenberg, I.
Stone, David
Stotz, Elmer H.
Strabanova, Sona
Straub, Ferenc B.
Streeter, John W.
Strominger, Jack L.
Strong, Lawrence E.
Stryer, Lubert
Stuewer, Roger H.
Stumpf, Paul K.
Sturdy, Herbert F.
Sturtevant, Julian M.
Subramanian, E.
Suh, Junghun
Summers, William C.
Sumner, James B.
Sund, Horst
Sundin, Olof
Surgenor, Douglas M.
Sutton, John
Swain, Philip W.
Swazey, Judith P.
Swigart, Edmund K.
Sykes, Peter
Sylven, Bengt
Synge, Richard L.M.
Szabo, Istvan
Szent-Györgyi, Albert
Szilard, Leo
Taborsky, George
Taft, Horace D.
Talalay, Paul
Tallan, Harris H.
Tam, James P.
Tanaka, Atsushi
Tanford, Charles
Tang, Jordan J.N.
Tarbell, Dean S.
Tarver, Harold
Tasso, Felix
Tatum, Edward L.
Tauber, Henry
Taurog, Alvin
Taylor, Charles H.
Taylor, Sterling P.
Teale, F.W.J.
Teich, Mikulas
Temkin, Owsei
Tepperman, Helen M.
Terry, Luther L.
Thackray, Arnold
Thanassi, John W.
Theodoropoulos, Dimitrios M.
Theoharides, Theoharis C.
Theorell, Hugo
Thoma, John A.
Thomas, Arthur L.
Thomson, Keith S.
Thompson, Robert C.
Thoms, Herbert
Thorn, George W.
Tietzman, Josephine
Tippo, Oswald
Tipson, Robert S.
Tiselius, Arne
Tishler, Max
Tobias, Julian M.
Todd, Alexander R.
Tomkins, Gordon M.
Toulmin, Stephen
Townsend, Leroy A.
Treffers, Henry P.
Travin, Adelaide
Trends in Biochemical Sciences
Trikojus, Victor M.
Trinity College (U.S.)
Trout, Gordon E.
Truman, David B.
Tsolas, Orestes
Tu, Anthony T.
Tuppy, Hans
Turekian, Karl K.
Turley, Emily J.
Turner, Frank M.
Turner, Henry A.
Tutzke, Dietrich
Tykocinski, Mark L.
Tyler, Morris
Tyutyunnik, V.M.
Udenfriend, Sidney
Ujiaky, Eugene
Uirbarger, H. Edwin
Umbreit, Wayne W.
Umezawa, Hamao
Underwood, E. Ashworth
Unitarian Service Committee
Ureta, Tito
Ussing, Hans H.
Valenzuela, Pablo
Vallee, Bert L.
Vallee, Richard B.
Vandendriessche, Laurent
Van Dyke, Henry B.
Van Lenten, Elizabeth J.
Van Ness, Michael
Van Sinderen, Alfred W.
Van Slyke, Donald D.
Vargha, Janos M.
Vars, Harry M.
Vaslow, Fred
Veber, Daniel F.
Veibel, Stig
Velick, Sidney F.
Velikovic, Dragutin
Vennesland, Birgit
Vernon, Charles A.
Vester, John W.
Vestling, Carl S.
Vickery, Hubert B.
Vicuna, Rafael
Villee, Claude A.
Vinogradov, Serge N.
Viseltear, Arthur J.
Vishniac, Wolf
Vithayathil, Paul J.
Vogel, Henry J.
Volkov, Vladimir A.
Von Feilitzen, Olof
Voynick, Irene M.
Wachsmuth, Ernst D.
Wacker, Warren E.C,
Waelsch, Heinrich
Wald, George
Waldschmidt-Leitz, Ernst
Walker, Eric A.
Walker, Theresa A.
Wallace, Bonnie
Wallach, Donald F.
Wallach, Michael
Wallenfels, Kurt
Waller, Erik
Wallerstein, Leo
Wallman, Lester J.
Walsh, Christopher
Wang, Jui H.
Wangensteen, Owen H.
Wankmüller, Armin
Ward, H. Lee
Warner, John H.
Warren, Katherine B.
Warren, Stuart G.
Wasserman, Harry H.
Waterman, Talbot H.
Wayne, Susan I.
Weaver, Warren
Webb, EDwin C.
Weber, Bruce H.
Weber, Gregorio
Weber, Klaus K.
Wehmiller, John F.
Weinberg, Barbara H.
Weinhouse, Sidney
Weiss, Paul
Weissman, Sherman M.
Weissmann, Gerald
Welch, Arnold D.
Wellcome Trust
Wells. Ellen B.
Werkman, Chester H.
Westfall, Richard S.
Westheimer, Frank H.
Wetlaufer, Donald B.
Weygand, Friedrich
Weyhe, Erhard
Whelan, William J.
Whipple, George H.
Whitaker, Douglas
Whitaker, John R.
White, Abraham
Whitehouse, Michael W.
Wiberg, Kenneth B.
Wickramasinghe, Rohan H.
Widmer, Francois
Widmer, Fred
Wieland, Albert
Wieland, Theodor
Wiggans, Donald S.
Wiggers, Harold C.
Wigler, Paul W.
Wigner, Eugene P.
Wilcox, Philip E.
Wildt, Rupert
Wilens, Sally
John Wiley & Sons
Wilhelmi, Alfred E.
Wilkinson, John A.
Williams, Carroll M.
Williams, Edwin E.
Williams, L. Pearce
Williams, Robley C.
Williams, Roger J.
Wilson, D. Wright
Wilson, Edwin B.
Wilson, Irwin B.
Wilson, Leonard G.
Wilson, Perry W.
Winitz, Milton
Winternitz, Milton C.
Wintersteiner, Oskar
Winzler, Richard J.
Wise, Ja Ann
Wishnia, Arnold
Witkop, Bernhard
Wold, Finn
Wolfenden, Richard V.
Wolfrom, Melville L.
Wolstenholme, Gordon E.W.
Wong, Pauline
Wood, Harland G.
Wood, John L.
Woodford, F. Peter
Woods, Donald D.
Woodward, Robert B.
Woolf, Harry
Wooolley, D. Wayne
Work, Elizabeth
Work, Thomas S.
Wright, Lemuel D.
Wrinch, Dorothy
Wu, Hsien
Wünsch, Erich
Würz, Hannelore
Wurmser, Rene
Wyatt, Gerard R.
Wyman, Jeffries
Wysowskyj, Helena
Yajina, Haruaki
Yale Review
Yale University News Bureau
Yamamura, Y.
Yanari, Sam
Yanofsky, Charles
Young, Frank G.
Young, Geoffrey T.
Yudkin, Warren H.
Zackson, Saul
Zamecnik, Paul
Zamenhof, Stephen
Zannis, Vassilis I.
Zelitch, Israel
Zeller, E. Albert
Zervas, Leonidas
Ziegler, James E.
Zierler, Kenneth L.
Zioudrou, Christine
Zuckerman, Solly
Zweig, Felix
Other Finding Aids
For an listing of correspondents with Joseph Fruton and an overview of his activities at Yale, please consult the Correspondents Index.
Biochemistry -- Study and teaching; Fruton, Joseph S. (Joseph Stewart), 1912-2007; Yale University -- Faculty
- Inventory, 13 linear feet (13 boxes)
  - BIOCHEMICAL RESEARCH NOTEBOOKS
    - Aboderin - Cirillo II (Box 1)
    - Cirillo III - Fairclough (Box 2)
    - Ferguson - Graff (Box 3)
    - Greenbaum - Husain (Box 4)
    - Ingram - Krenitsky I (Box 5)
    - Krenitsky II - Mycek III (Box 6)
    - Mycek IV - Okunda (Box 7)
    - Rajo - Taborsky III (Box 8)
    - Taborsky IV - Unidentified (Box 9)
    - Zioudrou (Box 10)
    - Fruton's Notebooks - misc. (Box 10)
    - Fruton's Notebooks - misc. (Box 11)
    - Theses by other people (Box 12)
    - Theses by other people (Box 13)
- Additional material, Accession 1985-M-011
  - Correspondence: School of Medicine, 1947-1983 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Yale University, 1952-1961 (Box 2)
  - Annual reports: Dept. of Phys. Chemistry, 1919-1967 (Box 2)
  - Professional activities: journals and societies, 1957-1975 (Box 3)
  - Professional activities: journals and societies Research notebooks, 1957-1975 (Box 4)
  - Research notebooks
    - Mathis; Lowbridge; Brownstein; Morgan (Box 5)
    - Sachder; Hollands; Trout; Del Pierre (Box 6)
    - Voynick; Inovye; Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Henes; Briggs; Bozler; Kuki; McNeil (Box 8)
  - Grant files, 1950-1980 (Box 9)
  - Student exams and grades, 1948-1980 (Box 9)
    General note
    Student records are restricted until January 1, 2056 as established by Yale Corporation regulations http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives.
- Additional material, Circa 1929-1993; Accession 1994-M-080; 12.5 linear feet (10 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Addition inventory by Diane E. Kaplan 1994 May
  Received from: Joseph Stewart Fruton, 1994 May 3
  The first nine boxes of material in this addition contain correspondence arranged in rough alphabetical order by name of correspondent. The last box of material, which is arranged by topic, documents Professor Fruton's activities at Yale.
  The files in the boxes on the box listing below are described in more detail in the list prepared by Professor Fruton, which follows the box listing. Names listed on Professor Fruton's list do not represent file folders, and materials of more than one individual or more than one topic may be grouped together in a single folder.
  Conditions Governing Access
  The correspondence is open for research.
  Access to Yale administrative and personnel files in Box 10 is restricted until 1 January 2069 by Yale University policy. http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives. Contact Public Services for information on requesting access to restricted university records.
  - Aa - Br (Box 1)
  - Bu - D (Box 2)
  - E - G (Box 3)
  - H - J (Box 4)
  - K - Mc (Box 5)
  - Maa - Q (Box 6)
  - Ra - Si (Box 7)
  - Sk - V (Box 8)
  - W - Z (Box 9)
  - Fruton's activities at Yale (Box 10)
    Appointments
    Committees on Appointments and Promotions (Tenure)
    Department of Biochemistry
    Department of Molecular Biology and Biochemistry
    Division of Science
    History of Science and Medicine
    Medical Library
    National Endowment for the Humanities (grant)
    National Institutes of Health (grants)
    National Science Foundation (grants)
    President's Committee on the Natural Sciences and Mathematics Silliman Lectures
    School of Medicine - Committee on Programs and Policy 1940-1944 (inherited from C.N.H. Long)
    Access to Yale administrative and personnel files is restricted until 1 January 2069 by Yale University policy. http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives. Contact Public Services for information on requesting access to restricted university records.
- Additional material, Circa 1927-1983; Accession 1994-M-083; 6.25 linear feet (5 boxes)
  Addition inventory by Diane E. Kaplan 1994 Jul
  Received from: Joseph Stewart Fruton, 1994 Jun 08
  - Public lectures, 1939-1993 (Box 1)
  - Course lectures
    - Physical chemistry 102, 1946 (Box 2)
    - Biology 140b, Circa 1979 (Box 2)
    - Biochemistry 107a: Biochemistry of peptides, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Enzyme catalysts and biochemical processes: Molecular biophysics and biochemistry 52b, Biology 50-2b, or Molecular biophysics and biochemistry 150b (4 folders), Circa1979 (Box 2)
    - Enzyme chemistry (5 folders), Circa 1979 (Box 2)
    - Biochemistry 100a and 101a (3 folders), undated (Box 2)
    - Biochemistry 100a and 101a (8 folders), undated (Box 3)
  - Research and subject files
    - Experimental physics, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Analytical dynamics, undated (Box 3)
    - Function theory, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - Physical chemistry, 1927 (Box 3)
    - Electricity and magnetism, undated (Box 3)
    - Carbohydrates, 1929-1938 (Box 3)
    - Organic chemistry (misc.), undated (Box 3)
    - General physiology, 1937-1939, undated (Box 3)
    - Molecular spectra, 1933 (Box 3)
    - Cystine derivatives, 1931, undated (Box 4)
    - Sulfhydryl compounds, 1932 (Box 4)
    - Proteolytic enzymes of blood, 1940-1951 (Box 4)
    - Salts of amino acids, 1941, undated (Box 4)
    - Trypsin and chymotrypsin, 1936-1938, undated (Box 4)
    - Papain, 1938, undated (Box 4)
    - Proteolytic enzymes (misc.), 1941, undated (Box 4)
    - Enzymes in tumors, undated (Box 4)
    - Activation. of proteolytic enzymes, 1939-1941 (Box 4)
    - Student papers (10 items), Circa 1951-1960, undated (Box 4)
    - Office of Science, Research, and Development: correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box 4)
      - OSRD CORR (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Office of Science, Research, and Development: reports, 1942-1944 (Box 4)
    - Pepsin, 1967, undated (Box 4)
    - Pepsin (diazoketones), Circa 1965-1966 (Box 4)
    - Pepsin: binding data, Circa 1967-1968 (Box 4)
    - Pepsin: fluorescence, undated (Box 4)
    - Pepsin: peptide synthesis, Circa 1981-1983 (Box 5)
    - Pepsin (misc.), 1974-1980 (Box 5)
    - Transamidation, Circa 1951 (Box 5)
    - Cathepsins, 1948-1960 (Box 5)
    - Cathepsin C, Circa 1959-1970 (Box 5)
    - Polymerization, 1953-1965 (Box 5)
    - Thermolysin, 1976-1983 (Box 5)
    - Dehydropeptidase, 1946, undated (Box 5)
    - Di-iodo Tyrosine Der (Baker), 1944 (Box 5)
    - Infra-red spectra of peptides, 1950-1951 (Box 5)
    - Peroxidases, undated (Box 5)
    - Phosphoramidic acids, Circa 1959-1960 (Box 5)
    - Bis-imidazole, 1964, undated (Box 5)
    - Esterase, Circa 1965-1970 (Box 5)
    - LDH isozymes, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972, undated (Box 5)
- Additional material, Accession 2002-M-064
  - Correspondence, A-Z, Circa 1994-2001 (Box 1)
  - Writings, 1931, undated (Box 1)
  - Lecture notes, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
  - Research notes, ca., 1953-1968 (Box 1)
  - "Semiannual List of the Publications of the Staff of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research,", 1934-1947 (Box 1)
- Additional material, circa 1900-2007; Accession 2008-M-012
  - Biographical, including school grades, curriculum vitae, biographical notes, awards, clippings, 1914-2005 (Box 1, Folder 1-14)
  - Correspondence, 1953-2007 (Box 1, Folder 15-23)
  - Lectures and seminars, 1939-1994 (Box 1, Folder 24-30)
  - Writings/research notes on topics including enzyme specificity, pepsin, and humorous Christmas carol adaptations, 1976-2002 (Box 1, Folder 31-35)
  - Yale Department of Biochemistry, guestbook and notes on history, 1952-circa 1992 (Box 1, Folder 36-37)
  - Conference memorabilia, 1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Guggenheim application for research grant, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Photographs, Circa 1900-2000
    - Documenting career (Box 1, Folder 40-42)
    - Family and friends, including J. S. Fruton, Sofia Simmonds, C. Fruton, and Jules Simmonds (Box 2, Folder 43-51)